Curriculum vitae

Owen McMonagle.

Phone: 086 331 6816 Email: owenmcmonagle1@gmail.com

Letterkenny, Co. Donegal. Portfolio: <u>softwareeureka.xyz/Portfolio.html</u>

About:

I'm a driven freelance software developer with five years' experience in developing complex and diverse applications. Seeking a challenging development opportunity in a worldwide distributor of software with an educational, creative and inspiring company culture.

Professional Experience:

Software Eureka (Nov 2014 – Sep 2016)

For two years I worked as a Freelance Software Developer serving local and international clients on the global market.

TriGem Computer Co, Ltd (Sep 2015 – Feb 2016)

Contracted by the So. Korean company TriGem to develop a Windows Media Server and Android Media Client called PC-Cast. Implemented VLC based media player, SSDP server discovery, real time media & file info, android UI design and network media player functionality through TCP/IP sockets.

CoinBitsy (May 2014 - Nov 2014)

A startup company formed here in Letterkenny. I was hired to develop a flagship game for the company called BitRunner. It was implemented with Java OpenGL using Slick2D and required animation, graphic design, game logic, image rendering, collision detection, OpenAL for music.

Education:

Software Developer (2011-2012) – FÁS & City and Guilds.

(FETAC 5&6) Level 2 & 3 Advanced Diplomas' for Software Developers.

Modules in: Program language and design.

Java development and design.

Testing software components.

COBOL development and design.

SQL management and database creation.

Requirements analysis and software specification.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Platforms: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, Red hat/Openshift), Windows, Android.

Languages: Core Java (Sockets, Concurrency, JSP, Servlets, Web Automation, Swing, JavaFX, Android).

Scripting: Inno Setup Install scripting, SQL.

Networking: TCP/IP, UDP/SSDP, HTML/CSS, HTTP REST, Data Mining, SSH, Apache, Apache Tomcat.

Databases: MSSQL/MySQL.

Methodologies: OOPD/Law of Demeter/Composition, UML, Structure, Flow and Component diagrams, Prototyping, Waterfall.

Tools: Eclipse, Android Studio, AIDE, Inno Setup, Visual VM/JConsole, JDoc, G.I.M.P.

QA: Test Plans/Test Scripts, Unit testing, Black & White box testing, Regression testing.

Notable APIS: VLCJ, Selenium, Jsoup, LibGDX, Slick2D.